Hello there!
This definitely looks like the
Labyrinth Stratum's Transfer Circle.
Well, dammit!
I bet Kerrioll tampered with the
Origin Stratum's Transfer Circle,
which I should have known he would do.
So, what you're telling me is
that we've lost control over it.
That's right.
But I don't think all is lost.
I seriously doubt his side
knows who got sent where.
The Transfer Circle doesn't have enough
power to return us to
Clearflow Lake Stratum,
I do know that much.
We'll need a magic stone that's
been charged up with power.
Then the Hunters Association
is the best place to start.
I agree.
On the outside, I'm just a big metal box.
But inside, I've still got a human soul.
In this new world of wonders,
I travel to and fro on the back
of my super strong partner, Lamas.
The name's Boxxo. Hello there.
That means yes, by the way.
That's right, surely!
to running out of preserved food, so
Boxo's arrival is quite the boon to us.
Thank you all.
The Labyrinth Stratum was struggling
with its own monster assault.
There are actual vending machines that
don't charge during times of disaster
so I tried taking a page from
their book by vending for free.
Director Labyrinth, have you
noticed any strangeness here lately?
You're referring to the wonkiness
with the transfer circle, I assume.
Well, not only that.
There's been a huge increase
in monster attacks, too.
They're controlled by the Netherlord.
That's the name of the Demon Lord's
nefarious left-armed general.
Goodness, I had no idea
it was that serious.
What a shock!
Though I shouldn't be surprised
that info hadn't reached me when
everyone knows I'm the least capable
out of all the Stratum directors.
I'm definitely not cut out for this job.
This poor director.
She has zero confidence.
We're saved!
His food is delicious!
I'm so thankful! Excellent.
Everyone seems happy with the food.
I checked for a magic stone at the item
shop, but it seems they're out of stock.
That's not good.
Well, we aren't going anywhere as long
as the transfer circle won't work.
I have an idea for how
to get a magic stone.
In the meantime, could you adjust the
transfer circle and see if that helps matters?
I'll try, but no promises.
You're a co-in there?
No, he's one step ahead, huh, Boxo?
Yes, I plan to venture into the labyrinth.
Huh? What's that?
Duh-er-axe t-er-la-insane!
Maybe some hunters survived the attacks.
Then we have no time to waste.
Thanks, Boxer.
That's helpful.
Don't worry.
We've got you.
Oh, thank you so very much.
Much?
Yep.
Seems like a normal
reaction to the sight of
a bear carrying a
cardboard vending machine.
Oh, this one is with me.
And, um, that one too.
Goodness, did that box just change shape?
The details can wait,
but for the time being,
you should think of our friend
as a special magic item.
Amazing.
Nice to meet you, magic item. Hello there.
Wow, the magic item responded.
As for the monsters, you may leave
it to these two to defeat them.
Everyone, cover your ears!
Something tells me they could have
handled this just fine without our help.
Wow, I've never heard of an Unasusu and
a Curacao that could overwhelm monsters.
These two are unique among their kind.
They're outstanding and very friendly.
And a certain someone's
power made them stronger.
A certain someone's power?
Color me curious.
I will clean up this mess,
so please be patient.
What's that dirt ball thingy?
I have to ask, what is
that dirt ball thingy?
I'll explain, but first things first.
Would it be an imposition if I
asked who the two of you might be?
Pardon my rudeness.
I'm Director Bear, head of the Hunter's
Association on Clearflow Lake Stratum.
This here is Boxxo, and he's a magic item
with the mind and soul of a human being.
He's fully sentient and a dependable
ally, someone you can talk to.
Hello there!
A human consciousness
contained within a magic item?
Wow, that's a bit like
that certain someone.
Who could she be talking about?
Now please allow me to
introduce myself and my friends.
I am Kikuyu.
The white in Asusu is Botan,
the black here is Kuroyata.
Based on what I saw of that battle,
these two are exceptionally strong.
Makes me wonder if the girl
has any power of her own?
My powers are the ability to
control a tiny amount of cold air.
And the ability to move
while concealing my presence.
Huh,
if she can mask her presence,
she could just hide while the
others handle all the combat!
Yes, that is true.
I am always relying on
Kuroyata and Botan to save me.
I guess that makes her an animal handler?
Oh no, I am not an animal handler.
They are smart enough to think on their
own and comprehend complex situations.
I am simply their friend
who benefits from that.
Kikuyu, would it be uncouth of me
to ask whom you're speaking with?
With me, that's who.
Oh, wait a minute.
Was she answering me even
though I wasn't vocalizing?
Why, I can hear the inner voice of any
material being that I am able to touch.
Whoa, for real?
Yes, for real.
Oh, but it was rude of me to do
that without asking permission.
I'm sorry. Ease! Okay!
Um, if you're hungry, we can have a
quick snack while we get acquainted.
Sure, let's do that.
Mealtime means it's my time, baby.
Good.
Then as thanks, I shall provide
the food for our little repass.
Huh?
She's not about to grow a plant
for us to eat right now, is she?
Whoa!
What?
How in the world does
that strange magic work?
Not only does this piece
of field absorb monsters?
and transform their bodies into nutrients!
but if you plant and water a seedling,
my friend can make it grow rapidly!
Did she call the dirt
ball a piece of field?
It will be a short while
before it finishes cooking,
so I will tell you a little
more about us in the meantime.
I must preface by saying that you might
find this story difficult to believe,
but it is all true.
And so, this is the story
of a very kind field.
Once upon a time, there was an old
woman living in a remote village.
Then one day, out of the blue,
she found that there was a
soul dwelling in her field.
It was a person who had come from
another world and turned into a field.
He couldn't speak to her, but every
day, the old woman cultivated him. Huh?
A soul inhabiting a field?
That's pretty weird.
Well, I guess a soul inside a
vending machine has no room to talk.
Also, since it came from another world,
our circumstances are very similar.
One day, the old woman passed away,
and the field was left all alone.
However, even a field like him had
managed to make some animal friends.
By animal, does she
mean Kuroyata and Botan?
He spent many quiet days with the animals,
until one day, a girl came
along, fleeing from something.
The field took pity on her and
rescued her from her pursuers.
The field wanted to save even more
people, and it went on a journey,
eventually arriving at a
fortified city in the north.
This might sound odd coming
from a vending machine,
but a field going on a journey
sounds too far-fetched even for me.
There was a fierce battle going on there
between the citizens and
the Demon Lord's forces.
The field saw it as an opportunity
and threw himself into the fight.
Despite being a field.
The field managed to drive
back the Demon Lord's forces,
earning a temporary time of
peace for the fortified city.
This field kicks ass.
Then he marched into the Demon Lord's
stronghold and fought fiercely,
allowing his friends to flee.
Once his friends had escaped, the
field shut down his consciousness.
If this story were about a hero,
I might be really inspired by it.
But the main character is a field.
Anyway, given how Kiku, you called
that thing the piece of field,
I can safely assume she and the
animals were the friends who got away.
We wanted to go see Field in his entirety,
but we couldn't make it past the
huge wall that's blocking the
road leading from the fortified
city to the Demon Lord's domain.
And then we heard a rumor we
thought could be of use to us,
that the Demon Lord's left-armed
general is here in this dungeon.
That information is what
led us to this stratum,
and that about catches us up to now.
Voxo! Voxo! Voxo?
So, that's the situation.
Yes, I understand.
Which means that even if I manage
to meet with the Netherlord,
it's still unlikely that I could
get him to tell me the way.
Oh, these are ready to eat! Here you go!
Thank you very much!
Oh, this is delicious, moist, and fluffy!
It's an explosion of
sweetness in my mouth!
I'm so delighted that you enjoy it!
But this isn't even
one-tenth as good as the
vegetables I used to
harvest from Field himself!
And one-tenth is even a
little too high, I thought.
Vegetables ten times better than that?
Impressive.
Oh, hey, they've got nothing to drink.
This will go well with
roasted sweet potatoes.
Oh my, what are those floating things?
Just wait, Boxo produced
some drinks for us.
All you do is open the lid like so.
Wow, it's so cold and tasty.
So Boxo has the ability
to serve cold drinks?
Oh, much more than just that.
He provides food and all
kinds of other goods.
He's a dependable guy, that Boxo. Oh, yes.
Field was able to produce any kind
of vegetable you could think of.
Boxo sounds surprisingly
similar to him after all.
Oh, right.
There's something I really
want to tell Kikuyu.
Did you say that you also came
here from another world? Yes.
It would seem the soul inside Boxo is
not of our world, just like your field.
I see.
Then I wonder if he might even have
come from the same place his field did.
If we manage to make our way to him,
you should try talking
to him about such things.
I'd love nothing more.
If he's Japanese like me, then I'll have
all kinds of things to discuss with him.
Yes!
We've joined forces and are
traveling with Kikuyu now.
Which means I get to ride in the cart.
It's getting darker by the second.
I think it would be wise if
we camped here for the night.
And what are these things?
They're delicious.
And these other round things are too.
I'm glad she seems to like the food,
but it's time to seal the deal.
And I know the way to a lady's
heart is through her taste buds.
Form change!
Wow, a whole new set of items?
Some eaters.
I've never seen so many sweets before!
Amazing!
This texture is completely
new to me, and I love it!
Let's try this next.
Delicious!
Though I must say,
this would be even more
outrageously delicious if
it had been made with the
fruit that field had grown.
Yeah, I'd like to sample that myself.
Uh, I'm sorry, but might I trouble
you for something to eat, too?
My bad, Director!
I completely forgot!
So, Boxo, what do you think of Kikuyu?
Ice-ca-ed. Agreed.
She's considerate and very smart, too.
So much so that her mind and
appearance don't seem to match.
He has a point.
You rarely see children her age
who have such strong character.
In fact, they don't exist.
Now that I think about it, it seems
unlikely that Kikuyu is a human child.
Based on her looks and abilities,
she must be some other race.
Probably a snow child.
A snow child?
I've heard that until a
snow child becomes an adult,
they retain the form of
a six-year-old child.
So their appearance doesn't
match their true age.
The snow children have
very special powers.
For that reason, they're a highly targeted
race and they're in danger of extinction.
In fact, until we met Kikuyu, I
thought they were already extinct.
Special powers that everyone goes after?
Legend has it that if you behead a snow
child on the day it becomes an adult,
they will transform into a magical
ice statue that will never melt.
As for the severed head,
it will continue to utter
curses that have the power
to contaminate entire
regions in one fell swoop.
I hear there are whole
nations that perish that way.
That's a killer power, but what it
takes to invoke it is too cruel.
Beheading someone to cast a
curse is a horrible thing to do.
And that's not the end of it either.
The Headless Ice Statue becomes a
sort of catch-all curse remover.
Just place it next to a cursed person,
and it will cleanse them of any hex.
It removes curses?
That means...
Co-A-P-A-T-E!
I have no doubt that it could
dispel Kerry Oil's son's affliction.
Oh man, if the Captain knew about this...
Which is why we mustn't utter
this knowledge to a solitary soul.
The secret must remain hidden.
Yes!
No matter what happens, we can't
let this girl end up a victim.
Oh, that's a...
A magic stone.
But I don't know if it's powerful enough
to get the transfer circle up and running.
Oh, that's right.
Without Hulemy, we don't know how much
power we need from the magic stones.
We'd better rendezvous with
Hulemy and see what's what.
Seems it can't pass through after all.
I already tried it once before,
but I don't believe there's any way
to get this piece of field through.
I heard this barrier can
detect monster wavelengths
and prevent the passage of those energies.
I'll bet the piece of
field-absorbed monsters soaked up
their wavelengths and the barrier
can't tell the difference.
I guess that makes sense.
But I can't leave field behind here
without worrying something bad will happen.
There's still one thing
that I'd like to try.
All right, Kikoyu, try to cross now.
Thank goodness! It worked!
So Bokso's barrier can successfully
interrupt the labyrinth barrier,
that's good to know.
Well, nice to meet you on this
side, Kikoyu, Kuroyata, and Botan.
Yes, Hulemy.
We thank you very much.
We're back to square one.
But we made some dependable friends,
and that's always a good thing.
Director Bear,
I finished adjusting the transfer circle
so I can accompany you all next time.
Oh, good.
You'll be most welcome.
Hello there!
We spent the night at an inn.
Then we ventured into
the labyrinth once again.
After much discussion,
we arrived at the conclusion that rather
than do an exhaustive search for stones,
we should try to defeat the dangerous Lava
Fiend monster and get its magic stone.
That lava fiend?
Well, it's more dangerous
than a stratum lord!
But both Hulemy and Director
Bear thought we'd be fine.
with such a formidable party.
Then shall I have Kuroyata fly above
the maze and seek out the lava fiend?
If you wouldn't mind.
Right.
Kuroyata, please do as I said!
Hmm.
We might as well end the search for today.
Let's start setting up camp. Good call.
So are you two gonna duke it out to
see who gets to make dinner tonight?
Voxo was in charge yesterday, so it
seems only fair that I do it tonight.
I could add da oo-it.
Oh no, you take it easy today.
Fresh vegetables are good for your skin,
and they also help prevent
all kinds of diseases.
I da oo-s will eat still.
Did you just say sweets?
Apparently, Hulemy craves sweets
after she's had a strenuous think.
And her favorite guilty pleasure
foods are all full of sugar.
Hmm.
Director Bear sounds non-committal,
but I know what my regulars' faves are.
Bear's gotta have their salmon.
Let's see if he can resist
this veritable salmon torrent.
Oh, dang, what's that?
I mean, why don't we just go with
Boxo's goods for this evening's meal?
Yes, let's.
No objections from me.
Hey, no fair, Boxo.
I look forward to serving you again.
Really?
With the sweet taste of
yesterday's victory still fresh,
I got some sleep last
night, a rarity for me.
Kikuyu stood watch from late
night until early morning,
so I was able to sleep soundly.
Now, I'd better start making
breakfast for everyone.
Good morning, Boxo!
I made some soup that's loaded with
vegetables, and it's very good for you!
She got me!
This was her secret plan all along!
Wow, so savory!
The flavor is amazing, and
it's so restorative, too!
Welcome back, Kariata!
Okay, thank you.
It seems Kuroyata has
found the Lava Fiend.
Since we know where it is,
I can share my strategy for
defeating it before we get there.
It should be somewhere around here. Oh!
There it goes now.
And that's a wall I built
using giant concrete slabs.
But I didn't stop there.
I built two walls.
Now why did I do such a thing, you ask?
That's why.
Have fun in your icy bath, Lava Fiend.
No heat stands a chance against
that much ice water, not even yours.
Though it might have only hardened your
outside, that's good enough for us.
According to Hulemy, the Lava
Fiend's weak point is its throat.
You might win an extra item!
I look forward to your next use.
Huh?
It regenerated?
That ain't good!
Whoa! What now?
Wait, could it be... no way!
A stratum split?
And isn't that...
Lamas?
How typical.
That doofus must have helped
herself to my inventions again.
Boxxo!
I'm glad you're okay!
Hold on, who's this bird guy? End!
I found you!
We're together again! Bad!
Wait, are you mad at me?
Yes!
You're evil!
What?
No, Boxxo, please don't be mad!
That was reckless.
You could have died if
something went wrong.
If you've got an explanation,
we would like to hear it, too.
Man, shouldn't this be the part
where we're happy to see each other?
Talk, Lamas.
Tell us what happened since we last saw
you and how you came to fall from the sky.
Well, you see, right
after I last saw you guys,
Director Origin and I were lucky enough to
transfer to the Clear Flow Lake stratum.
Then I remembered how
Director Bear said if you hit
a stratum split real hard
at exactly the right spot,
you might be able to make it split again.
And then Hulami's magic item
that lets you safely drop
from high up and the one
that freezes water were just,
like, right there.
And Hulemy wasn't around
to ask, so I used him.
I'm sorry.
And so I kind of punched the
frozen pond with all my might.
And then the stratum split again.
and I just sort of tumbled
down into the crack.
Well, here I am.
Those deep sighs are definitely warranted.
That was all too impulsive.
But Lamas, what if we hadn't
been in the labyrinth stratum?
What would you have done?
Well, uh, I don't know.
I had a feeling you were here.
That's quite the leap of faith!
The most important thing
is that you're safe, Lamas.
But I want you to realize we're all angry
because we care about you
and what happens to you.
Yeah, I'm sorry if I had you guys worried.
Well, we're together
and that's what matters.
You're safe.
Yeah, Hulemy, I am back!
. . .
No memory, the words of
the way over the world?
I'll move on to the same time!
I'll keep my own love.
I'll keep my own memory.
As I can't wait for my own time!
I'll keep my own love.
You could even win a reward!
I look forward to serving you again!